Survival began with a song
Bessie is a drama, music, tv movie film directed by Dee Rees.
The story of legendary blues performer, Bessie Smith, who
rose to fame during the 1920s and '30s.
Bessie Smith, played by Queen Latifah.
Ma Rainey, played by Mo'Nique.
Richard, played by Mike Epps.
Lucille, played by Tika Sumpter.
Jack Gee, played by Michael Kenneth Williams.
William 'Pa' Rainey, played by Charles S. Dutton.
Bessie is a 2015 HBO TV film about the American blues singer Bessie Smith, and focuses on her
transformation as a struggling young singer into "The Empress of the Blues".
The film is directed by Dee Rees, with a screenplay by Rees,
Christopher Cleveland and Bettina Gilois.
Queen Latifah stars as Bessie Smith, and supporting roles are played by Michael Kenneth
Williams as Smith's first husband Jack Gee, and Mo'Nique as Ma Rainey.
The film premiered on May 16, 2015.
By the following year Bessie was the most watched HBO
original film in the network's history.
The film was well received critically and received four Primetime
Emmy Awards, winning for Outstanding Television Movie.
The film explores themes of blues, lgbt, woman director, black lgbt, lesbian.
The tone is emotional.